Would Dr. Zane, Dr. Khoury please. Dr. Nizar Zane is going to induct Dr. Wael
Khoury.
Dr. Nizar Zane is the chairman and medical director of his global patient
services at Cleveland Clinic.
He's the chief of hepatology and medical director of liver transplantation at
Cleveland Clinic.
He's also well known for his academic achievements, his active inmates at the
local, national and international levels.
Dr. Nizar Zane will induct Dr. Wael Khoury.
Thank you for the kind invitation to do this presentation.
With all the strength and wisdom of Wael, I think he made a mistake by choosing
me to do this presentation.
But in fact, to be truthful, on Saturday I spent almost an entire day trying to
write remarks.
I tried to think of Wael and since I met him, what I know about him, what he
had done.
And it ended up being probably seven or eight pages and then I had to cut it
down.
So he is a very accomplished person.
So it is very humbling and a great honor to introduce someone I have admired
for so many years.
And I hope he was inspired to reach the standards he set and achieved himself.
For that I thank you all.
He is un-exordinally outstanding and outstanding in many ways.
Dr. Khoury is blessed with an enormous self-confidence that had its roots in
his knowledge, skills and in his great intellectual capabilities.
His mind has sort of unshaken with voice and serenity that helped him remain
unfilled and true to his principles.
As he represented and passionately defended the values of a structured woman
and a divided Syrian American society.
At his level of honesty, elegance and cultural refinement, he was above those
strategies.
Dr. Wael Khoury was and continues to be the glue of our local diverse Arab
American society here in Cleveland.
It was once said that the apen does not fall far from the tree.
Dr. Wael Khoury and his father are undoubtedly made from the same cloth.
The late Mr. Shahada Khoury is an intellectual icon in Syria and across the
Arab world.
He was a leader in modernizing Arabic language for its use in contemporary
sciences.
Clearly Wael was heavily and positively influenced by his father's passion for
knowledge and acquired many of his leadership skills.
As a distinguished member of the local medical community for many years, Dr. Khoury
served as the President of Cardiology Associates of Cleveland
and as the Head of Cardiology at Merriman Hospital for over 130 consecutive
years.
He was appointed as the Chief of Staff at Merriman between 1993 and 1995 and as
the Vice President for Medical Affairs between 1995 and 2001.
Arguably, one of his best accomplishments during these years was his successful
petitioning at the state level for hospitals with less than 250 dead capacity
to have cardiac catheterization facilities.
This achievement saved many lives when patients did not have the luxury of time
to be transferred to larger medical centers.
But that's not why we are here tonight.
We are here tonight to acknowledge the many contributions of the man with an
inherent and true passion for public service.
Dr. Wael Khoury embodies all the values of public servants working for the
common good for social progress and equality.
It was his passion for public service that led Dr. Khoury nearly 20 years ago
to join the Cleveland Council on the Board of Affairs at CCWA.
With whom he shared a vision and a mission.
Soon he became a member of the board at CCWA and ever since has actively worked
to promote the Council's mission.
That is to inspire engagement in international affairs and work culture through
education, public dialogue and citizen diplomacy.
Wael served as the Chairman of the Board of CCWA between 2012 and 2015 and
resumed his position again in 2016.
As a Chairman, Wael never sees to us how the Council can reach out to more
Clevelanders, especially the youth.
CCWA's modern United Nations program now brings nearly 54 schools and 1,800
students.
Dr. Wael Khoury also put his heart and soul into ensuring that Cleveland gains
an awareness and benefits of serious rich and colorful culture.
Thus he became the founding President of the Syrian American Cultural Council
in 2005.
Out of that we never knew the vision of having a Syrian garden among Cleveland's
great cultural gardens along Martin Luther King Boulevard.
Wael saw his dream fulfilled in September of 2015 with the official
inauguration of the Unmagnificent Syrian Garden, a worthy tribute to the deep
history and culture of Syria.
Recently, thanks to his time as commitment to the concept of cultural gardens
Dr. Khoury was elected to be the President of the Executive Board of the
Cleveland Cultural Gardens Federation.
In fact, I believe he started his role this month or last month.
As we celebrate the accomplishments of Wael, it would quantity a half-finished
presentation without speaking of the woman besides him, who will not met you
but with Wael.
I don't know how that makes me feel. His wife Sousa, and I talked with Sousa,
and I talked with Speed and Earth on her own.
Not only is it a symbol of elegance and class, Sousa, the inspiration and the
energy that keeps Wael enthusiastically working on his many projects.
This is apparent to all of us who were privileged to spend a lot of time with
the Khoury family.
Sousa is an educator by profession and a dedicated civic leader promoting our
city through her own work with the Cleveland Film Festival among several other
societies and foundations.
Sousa also ensures that Wael is up and working all night long. This may be
interpreted in many different ways.
But what I meant by it is that if you know Wael, Khoury, you always receive
emails from Wael between 2 and 5 AM.
And you can't help but wonder what this man ever sees.
In fact, at night between 2 and 5 AM, there are only two types of communication.
Tweets from President Trump's and emails from Trump's.
So we said earlier that the apple does not fall far from the tree.
The legacy of Wael would undoubtedly continue into the next generation of Khoury
family.
Sousa and Wael are less than four lovely and equally as accomplished children,
not only achievers by every academic standard, but filled with their parents'
aspirations for civil and community service and for the honorable purpose of
bridging acts among culture.
Two of the four children, Rana and Tz
Tz